Hello it's Scott Manley here.
你好 我是斯科特-曼利
Yesterday we took another step towards science fiction
昨天 我们又向科幻小说迈出了一步
when it was announced that the US Air Force Research Laboratory was going to start taking a serious look at
当它宣布美国空军研究实验室将开始认真研究
suborbital transportation of materials cargo whatever around the world using rockets right.
使用火箭在世界范围内进行材料货物的亚轨道运输 对吗？
I mean the official announcements talking about the this being a Vanguard program
我的意思是 官方的公告说这是一个先锋计划
as part of their science and technology strategy for the next decade.
作为他们未来十年的科学和技术战略的一部分
And that Space Force would be the lead service for the program.
而太空部队将是该计划的主导部门
And I'm not really sure what lead service means in this context
我不太清楚在这种情况下主导服务意味着什么
but I'm sure the concept of Space Force sending military assets around the world using rockets
但我确信 太空部队使用火箭将军事资产送到世界各地的概念
sounds a lot like science fiction.
听起来很像科幻小说
Well at least sending military hardware in that manner
嗯 至少以这种方式发送军事硬件
without intending them to well explode on arrival ICBMs, right.
而不打算让它们在抵达洲际弹道导弹上爆炸 对吧
Sci-fI has things like Starship troopers dropping onto the battlefield and pods
科幻小说里有像星际飞船士兵投放到战场上的东西 还有吊舱
and in the 1950s and 1960s the idea of deploying troops via rocket was actually investigated broadly
在20世纪50年代和60年代 通过火箭部署部队的想法实际上得到了广泛研究
and it produced like this marvelous concept art showing something
它产生了像这样奇妙的概念艺术 展示了一些东西
that would make Starship look pretty small in comparison.
这将使 "星舰 "看起来相当小
But in this case it's not about building anything new.
但在这种情况下 这并不是要建造什么新东西
The official wording announcing the program specifically says
宣布该计划的官方措辞特别说到
that the Air Force Research Laboratory will lead a science and technology effort
空军研究实验室将领导一项科学和技术工作
to determine the viability and utility of
以确定使用现有大型商业火箭的可行性和实用性
using existing large commercial rockets for the Department of Defense global logistics.
使用现有的大型商业火箭用于国防部的全球物流
So look this kind of restricts it to things that are already in existence.
所以看起来这有点将它限制在已经存在的东西上
It's very likely just going to be a bunch of people
这很可能只是一群人
sitting in a room and doing math and running simulations playing Kerbal Space Program
坐在一个房间里 做数学题 运行模拟 玩Kerbal太空计划
and writing a report based on what's commercially available.
并根据商业上可用的东西写一份报告
And based on the current market the only thing that seriously fits the bill is SpaceX's Starship right.
而根据目前的市场 唯一符合条件的是SpaceX的星际飞船
I mean the concept art pretty much screams make it not quite look like SpaceX
我的意思是 概念图几乎是在叫嚣着让它看起来不太像SpaceX
and the truth is however the Starship is not really an ideal design for many technical reasons
而事实是 由于许多技术原因 星际飞船并不是一个理想的设计
but we'll get back to that.
但我们会回到这个问题上
Right now the fastest way to move stuff around the world is probably aircraft.
现在 在世界范围内移动东西的最快方式可能是飞机
Things like the C-130 Hercules, the C-5 Galaxy.
像C-130大力士 C-5银河
These are subsonic.
这些都是亚音速的
They will take a day to get around to the other side of the world with your precious cargo.
它们需要一天的时间才能把你的珍贵货物运到世界的另一端
But the US military already has bases all over the world
但美国军方已经在世界各地拥有基地
and so if you've got something that's needed to be transported over that distance
因此 如果你有东西需要被运输到那么远的距离
it actually makes some sense to have caches of this stuff at bases around the world.
实际上 在世界各地的基地存放这些东西是有意义的
And the nice thing about air transport is
空中运输的好处是
it is actually possible to air drop some of these things into locations
它实际上有可能将其中一些东西空投到需要的地方
where it's needed and where the aircraft can't land.
在需要它的地方 而飞机不能降落
So my question is is there a real need for suborbital transport
所以我的问题是 是否真的需要亚轨道运输？
which is again able to move stuff anywhere on the earth in under an hour.
它又能在一小时内把东西送到地球上的任何地方
And I'm very skeptical.
我非常怀疑
I think the scenarios where it works are very narrow.
我认为它发挥作用的场景非常狭窄
But the US Department of Defense has deep pockets
但美国国防部有很深的口袋
and might end up investing in something even if it never actually gets used.
并可能最终投资于一些东西 即使它实际上从未被使用
Suborbital transportation makes the transport very fast
亚轨道运输使运输速度非常快
but it still takes time to load and unload at each end.
但它仍然需要时间在每一端进行装载和卸载
And the loading time you also have to account for things like propellant loading time
而且装载时间还必须考虑到推进剂装载时间等因素
which is non-trivial for a 5000 ton rocket.
对于5000吨的火箭来说 这是非同小可的
You can't keep a cryogenically fueled Starship on the pad ready to go at a moment.
你不可能把装有低温燃料的星际飞船放在平台上随时准备出发
Notice it takes about 30 minutes to fuel up the Falcon 9
请注意 给猎鹰9号加燃料大约需要30分钟
and it will probably take longer to load up Starship with all its propellants.
并可能需要更长的时间来装载星际飞船的所有推进剂
Now it can be presumed that
现在可以推测
the massive extra resources needed for suborbital delivery will make it much more expensive than aircraft.
亚轨道运送所需的大量额外资源将使其比飞机昂贵得多
Currently the Falcon 9 rideshare program costs of about 5000 dollars per kilogram.
目前 "猎鹰9号 "共享项目的成本约为每公斤5000美元
Now the scale of something like Starship might reduce that to a fraction of this.
现在 像Starship这样的规模可能会将其减少到这个数字的一小部分
Whatever you want to ship around the world
无论你想在世界范围内运输什么
it will have to justify this cost of getting there a day before other supplies.
它将不得不证明比其他物资早一天到达那里的成本是合理的
And the good news of course on this is
当然 这方面的好消息是
that the US military has lots of stuff that costs more than five thousand dollars per kilogram.
美国军方有很多东西 每公斤的成本超过5000美元
So let's look at that glorious concept art again.
因此 让我们再看看那幅光辉的概念图
It shows trucks driving away from a rocket with red cross flags
它显示了从火箭上开走的卡车 上面有红色的十字旗帜
suggesting that this monster rocket dropped into some disaster zone
暗示这个怪物火箭掉进了某个灾区
with materials to help the locals get back on their feet.
带有帮助当地人重新站起来的材料
And the US military is actually regularly involved in disaster relief operations
而美国军队实际上经常参与救灾行动
but if you're watching something like a hurricane or floods or bad weather
但如果你看到的是像飓风、洪水或恶劣天气这样的事情
then the odds are the planners already have enough of a head start to be preparing for the recovery
那么规划者已经有足够的先机为恢复做准备了
by moving materials closer to the place they'll be needed as soon as landing as possible.
尽可能快地把物资运到需要的地方
Assuming that someone competent is in charge.
假设有能力的人在负责
Earthquakes and tsunami on the other hand they don't have offer any warning.
另一方面 地震和海啸是没有任何警告的
So sure there might be some advantage in
因此 可以肯定的是 在地震和海啸发生后的几个小时内 可能会有一些好处
getting relief to some people hours afterwards rather than days afterwards.
让一些人在几小时后而不是几天后得到救济可能有一些好处
But again this is very much a niche application.
但这又是一个非常小众的应用
The image also shows a rocket landed vertically
该图片还显示了火箭垂直降落的情况
and this is what Starship intends to do
而这正是Starship打算做的事情
but it's not really a great option for loading and unloading.
但对于装卸来说 这并不是一个真正的好选择
Starship has to land vertically because the engines are in the bottom
星际飞船必须垂直着陆 因为引擎在底部
and it uses the same engines for boosting into orbit and for landing back from space
而且它使用相同的发动机来推动进入轨道和从太空降落回来
because you're trying to optimize for the mass.
因为你正试图对质量进行优化
But let's be clear the wording surrounding the program
但我们要清楚围绕该计划的措辞
it does give them flexibility to consider other options from other contractors
它确实给了他们灵活性来考虑来自其他承包商的其他方案
who might want to throw their hat in the ring if they smell some DoD contract money.
如果他们嗅到了国防部合同资金的味道 他们可能想把他们的帽子扔进戒指里
If you were wanting to build something more appropriate for
如果你想建造一些更适合于
landing in an unprepared area and offloading cargo
在没有准备好的地方降落并卸载货物
I still don't think that parachutes are going to be a viable option simply
我仍然不认为降落伞将是一个可行的选择 仅仅是
because we're talking something very large.
因为我们谈论的是非常大的东西
But redesigned rocket-based lander which puts the cargo closer to the ground
但重新设计的火箭着陆器 将货物放在离地面更近的地方
would solve the massive problems of unloading cargo quickly from Starship after landing in the location
将会解决星际飞船着陆后迅速卸下货物的巨大问题
which may not have any specialist cargo handling gear.
可能没有任何专业的货物处理设备
I mean on the other hand Starship might work well if you're delivering cargo between US bases
我的意思是 另一方面 如果你在美国基地之间运送货物 星际飞船可能很好用
but again if you're delivering it between bases you have to ask what kind of cargo is so valuable
但是 如果你要在基地之间运送货物 你必须要问 什么样的货物是如此有价值的？
that it isn't just cheaper to have extra copies on hand at bases around the world.
以至于在世界各地的基地都有额外的副本 这不是更便宜吗？
One item actually which can't be easily copied is people
实际上 有一个项目是不容易复制的 那就是人
if there's some situation that requires a specific person or specific group of people
如果有一些情况需要一个特定的人或特定的一群人
to be on the ground in a specific place as soon as possible.
尽快赶到一个特定的地方
Sure this is something that might actually work might offer an advantage.
当然这是可能真正起作用的东西可能提供一个优势
The 1960s concept are actually shows troops deploying via a giant inflatable slide
20世纪60年代的概念实际上显示了部队通过一个巨大的充气滑梯进行部署
which seems sub-optimal.
这似乎是次优的
After a rocket launch hot re-entry and fiery landing
在经历了火箭发射的高温再入和火热的着陆之后
it would be unfortunate to injure yourself on a giant inflatable slide.
如果在一个巨大的充气滑梯上受伤 那将是不幸的
The trajectory that a sub-orbital flight has to follow means that there's no flexibility on routes.
亚轨道飞行必须遵循的轨迹意味着在路线上没有灵活性
You have to follow a great circle
你必须遵循一个大圆圈
and that means the vehicle from certain destinations will override territories
而这意味着来自某些目的地的飞行器将超越领土
at an altitude that might would be considered in orbit.
在一个可能被认为是在轨道上的高度
And this will probably lead to complaints from some
而这可能会导致一些人的抱怨
but there's basically very little that can be done to stop it
但基本上没有什么可以做的来阻止它
unless a country wants to actually go to war and deploy anti-satellite things.
除非一个国家想真正开战并部署反卫星的东西
Launching suborbital military rockets as well to fly over somebody else's territory
发射亚轨道军事火箭并飞越别人的领土
is also going to be a political minefield.
也将是一个政治雷区
Not just because it's like flying over other people's territory with military stuff
不仅仅是因为它就像在别人的领土上飞过军事东西一样
but hey how do that that's not a nuclear missile strike incoming.
但是 如何做到这一点 这不是一个核导弹袭击的到来
The US actually has an ongoing project called Prompt Global Response(Strike)
美国实际上有一个正在进行的项目 叫做全球快速反应（打击）
to deliver conventional weapons via something like an ICBM.
以通过类似洲际弹道导弹的东西来运送常规武器
And one of the major sticking points is the potential confusion and potential for retaliation
其中一个主要的症结是潜在的混乱和报复的可能性
if another nation suspects that the launch is nuclear.
如果另一个国家怀疑发射的是核弹
When the global policy on averting nuclear conflict is mutually assured destruction
当避免核冲突的全球政策是相互确保摧毁时
there's not a huge room amount of room for nuance in responses to launches in other territories.
在对其他领土上的发射作出反应时 就没有很大的空间来进行微调
So look I don't see this ever being deployed at least not in the near term.
因此 我认为这永远不会被部署 至少在短期内不会
Technologically it's absolutely possible to build something that does this.
从技术上讲 制造这样的东西是绝对可能的
Starship isn't quite right for the task.
星舰并不完全适合这项任务
But if the DoD wanted I'm sure they could get something more in line with their needs.
但如果国防部想要 我相信他们可以得到更符合他们需求的东西
And there's a lot of defense contractors out there
而且有很多国防承包商在那里
that would be more than happy to take the money for such a project.
他们会非常乐意接受这样一个项目的资金
But I will say that I'd see suborbital transportation of military hardware
但我想说的是 我认为军事硬件的亚轨道运输
as much more likely to happen than point-to-point civilian passenger transport
比点对点民用客运更有可能发生
because you both actually have similar problems in terms of politics.
因为你们在政治方面实际上都有类似的问题
But the military actually have the connections to help circumvent these problems.
但军方实际上有帮助规避这些问题的关系
I'm Scott Manley. Fly safe.
我是斯科特-曼利 飞行安全
[Music]
[音乐]